

MD NURUL HASAN

I want to engage myself in the field of Mechanical engineering where I explore my talent and my knowledge. I want to enhance my knowledge to develop my career. So, I would like to join a field where I can use my skills and experiences and render my services to humankind most efficiently as a potential and an innovative engineer.



Uttar Bishil, Road No-1, Sornali Tower, Mirpur-1, Dhaka-1216.



22.07.1993



01674329551 hasan.iiumg1739013@gmail.com

SOCIAL MEDIA



linkedin.com/in/md-nurulhasan



live:hasan.iiumg1739013

EXPERIENCE

03.2022 - present

Walton

Senior Deputy Assistant Director

- New product development and concept design.
- Research, Development and Designing gear transmission system of Electric Vehicle.

06.2018 - 03.2021

International Islamic University of Malaysia

Research Assistant

Working with an electric vehicle team to developing gearbox and transmission systems.

10.2019 - 09.2021

Universal Cellular Engineering Services Sdn Bhd

Assistant Engineer

• Outsource as an Assistant Engineer in TM Malaysia RAN Project.

03.2017 - 02.2018

PRAN-RFL GROUP (Saudi Lubricant Section)

Operation assistant manager

- I look after the industries Gas and Diesel generator engine oil and all industries compressor's oil and collect data
- Developing the new design of Mobil oil product and customize with newly developed jar and also working with the marketing department to create new advertising for the product and quality.

EDUCATION

06.2018 - 04.2021

International Islamic University Malaysia

MSc in Automotive Engineering (Research Mode)-CGPA 3.67

05.2012 - 02.2017

Chittagong University of Engineering & Technology

BSc in Mechanical Engineering-CGPA 3.16

07.2009 - 07.2011

Dhaka Residential Model College

HSC (Science-GPA 5.00)

01.2007 - 03.2009

Dhaka Residential Model College

SSC (Science- GPA 5.00)



BACHELORS PROJECT

Fabrication of a UAV with locating its position Supervised by Dr TILOK KUMAR DAS, Assistant professor Department of Mechanical Engineering, (CUET).

POST-GRADUATE PROJECT

Development of Autonomous Electromagnetic 2 speed Gearbox for EV 'supervised by Prof. Dr. MD Ataur Rahman, Department of Mechanical Engineering, IIUM.

PUBLICATION

PATENT:

Autonomous Electro-Ferromagnetic 2- speed Gearbox for Electric Vehicle. Product submitted by PATENTWORTH (Patent Agent) to MyPO.

Book Chapter:

Rahman Ataur, Nurul Hassan, Sany Ihsan (2020) Fuzzy Adaptive Autonomous Electromagnetic 2-speed Gearbox for Electric Vehicle. Recent Developments in Engineering Research Vol.10, 978-93-90431-11-3 (Print ISBN), 978-93-90431-19-9 (E ISBN), pp.41-60.

Journal Article:

- [1] Rahman, Ataur, Nurul Hasan, Sany Izan Ihsan (2021) Autonomous two speed gearbox for electric vehicle. International Journal of Automotive Technology, Springer (It is in Press) (Q1 Journal, IF 1.269).
- [2] Rahman, Ataur, Nurul Hasan, Sany Izan Ihsan (2021) Fuzzy Logic Controlled Two Speed Electromagnetic Gearbox for Electric Vehicle.. Internation Journal of Technology, Universitas Indonesia (Q2 Journal, IF 2.86).
- [3] Ataur Rahman, Nurul Hassan, Abdul Hassan Jaafar, AKM Mohiuddin, Sany Ihsan Izan (2019) Study on the development of electromagnetic seamless two-speed gearbox for EV. International Journal of Recent Engineering and Technology, Vol.7(6S), 147-152.
- [4] Rahman, Mohammed Ataur and Hasan, MD Nurul and Zaki, Mohd (2020) Modeling and validation of electric vehicle driveline architecture using bond graph. Test Engineering and Management, 82 (January - February 2020). 15154-15167. ISSN 0193 - 4120.

SKILLS

Good communication skills.

Leadership and teamwork mentality.

Interested in new research and take challenges.

Interested to improve problem-solving skills.

Effective interpersonal skills and flexibility.

Solid Works, Ms-Excel, Ms-word

HOBBY











Technology

Music

Travelling

REFERENCES

Dr. MD.ATAUR RAHMAN

Professor.

Department of Mechanical Engineering International Islamic University of Malaysia

Phone No: - +601135352708.

Email - arat@iium.edu.my

Dr. Muhammad Mahbubur Rashid Associate Professor. Department of Mechatronics Engineering International Islamic University of Malaysia Phone No: - +60163132236. Email-mahbub@iium.edu.my

